Cédric Rochefolle

Development Manager / Senior Software Engineer

A strong and self-motivated Software Engineer, experienced with large scale e-commerce as well as small, fine tuned websites. Development Manager with proven track in a large company using Agile efficiently.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Development Manager - Agoda Services Co., Ltd.

Jul 2015 - To date

Manager duties:

- Managed a team of up to 13 software engineers
- · Recruited for Front-End department
- Trained new joiners in on-boarding programs
- Collected product/business data and utilized it to make strategic decisions
- · Collected scrum data to improve velocity

Tech lead duties:

- Improved web-application server-side performance by 75%
- · Contributed to the constant evolution of the website:
 - Migration to use the back-end micro-services
 - Migration from KnockoutJS to ReactJS
- Various contributions to company and Bangkok tech community:
 - Presenter of 2 Meetups in Bangkok: TypeScript training and Full Open-Source CI/CD for a netcore+reactjs application
 - o Online training material

Senior Software Engineer - Agoda Services Co., Ltd.



- Development of Agoda website, operation support: ASP.NET, JQuery
- Re-wrote a part of the main funnel of the website:
 - ASP.NET MVC 5 and WebAPI
 - KnockOutJS
- · Introduced better software development practices:
 - Benchmarked Dependency Injection libraries and identified best fit
 - Automated code coverage, with a maintained KPI > 70%
 - Added static code analysis with SonarQube

Technical Director - Yesijoin Co., Ltd.

🛅 Jul 2011 - Nov 2013

- Designed and implemented www.yesijoin.com from scratch using J2EE technology:
 - web-application architecture, EJB 3.0 and JSF (Primefaces)
 - · Integration with payment gateways
 - o Email marketing via Amazon Email
 - Deployment on AWS instance
 - o Automated testing with selenium
- Built a 3 developers team
- Created a flash-mob interactive device
- Created a web-crawler to collect condos/apartments for sale/rent information

Technical Director - Entiera Co., Ltd.

iii Jun 2008 - Mar 2011

- Software architecture and design of a J2EE intranet:
 - Converted development environment from Windows to Ubuntu increased team velocity by 15%
 - Customized data visualization tool for Verizon (NY office)
- Performed demos and customized JasperServer Professional
- · Recruited software engineers

And before that...

🗰 2001 - May 2008

Various software engineer positions in:

- Property Management Systems in hospitality industry
- Biometric and security industry
- Electronics and Jewelry ERP
- · System engineer in telecommunication company

jssirode@gmail.com ☑

+66 (0)81 807 3420 🔲

Bangkok, Thailand **Q**

https://github.com/jscoobyced 🖸

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cedricrochefolle in

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Management

Team Manager, Educator / Trainer, Scrum / Agile, Team Transformer

Software Engineering

Application at scale, Design Review / Code Review, Coding Standard / Static Code Analysis, Web-Security / OWASP

Software Development

ASP.NET, Netcore, Java (J2SE, J2EE), ReactJS, KnockoutJS, TypeScript, HTML/CSS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Develop sawan.io website as a medium to keep learning on software development (
 - ReactJS, netcore 2.2, AppVeyor build, Codecov, SonarQube and docker)
- 2. Home CCTV connected to Raspberry Pi 3 and SSH tunnel to VPS for remote monitoring
- Various base docker images to facilitate build and hosting of web-application

SOFT SKILLS

Public speaking (assistant professor in English for Thai government officials), KPI definition ("Start with WHY"), 1-on-1 meeting

EDUCATION

- Master in Network Systems at University Henry Poincare, France
- · Degree in Electronics at University Du Montet, France

LANGUAGES

- French (native)
- English
- Thai